R. J. Scott Cartoons
R. J. Scott Cartoons
1960-1967
Scott, Roland J.
1 linear ft.
Original cartoon panels from Scott's Scrap Book and Sally's Sallies.
2652492
Biographical History
Roland Jack Scott (1886-1968), professionally known as R. J. Scott, was an American cartoonist and creator of the comic strips Scott's Scrap Book and Sally's Sallies.
Originally from Indianapolis, Scott began his cartooning career with the Indianapolis Star circa 1900. In 1921 he made his way west to Phoenix where he worked as a cartoonist for The Arizona Republican (later renamed The Arizona Republic). After stints with papers in New York and Cleveland, Scott eventually signed with King Features Syndicate in 1931. He returned to Arizona the following year where he remained producing his syndicated panels until his retirement in July of 1967. R. J. Scott died April 4, 1968 at the age of 81.
[source: Obituary, The Arizona Republic, 6 April 1968]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The R. J. Scott Cartoons collection contains 6 original cartoon panels from Scott's Scrap Book (1960-64), a "did-you-know?" panel strip, and 6 original cartoon panels from Sally's Sallies (1966-67), a panel strip focused on a newly married couple and their social milieu.
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged separately in chronological order.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Scott, Roland J.; King Features Syndicate.; Scott's scrap book (comic strip); Sally's sallies (comic strip); Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of R. J. Scott, 1967.
Inventory
- Sally's Sallies cartoon panels, 6 items; (traces of graphite, pen and ink on illustration board, 6 ¾ x 7 ¾ in.)
  - 08/02/1966 (Box 1)
  - 10/05/1966 (Box 1)
  - 10/08/1966 (Box 1)
  - 11/25/1966 (Box 1)
  - 12/24/1966 (Box 1)
  - 01/21/1967 (Box 1)
- Scott's Scrap Book cartoon panels, 6 items; (traces of graphite, brush, pen and ink, paste-overs on illustration board, 11 x 11 ½ in.)
  - 11/10/1960 (Box 1)
  - 12/17/1960 (Box 1)
  - 12/19/1960 (Box 1)
  - 12/21/1960 (Box 1)
  - 08/22/1963 (Box 1)
  - 01/27/1964 (Box 1)